# Alexis Pequeño Cortez

+51 930 645 152 | linkedin.com/in/alexis-pequeno

#### **PROFILE**

Graduate in Computer Science, with significant experience in designing, developing, and leading teams for large-scale software projects. Demonstrated ability to lead multidisciplinary teams towards achieving business objectives while maintaining high standards of quality and technical excellence.

## **SKILLS**

Languages: Java, Python, Rust, Go, Javascript, SQL, Bash, C, Ruby, HTML, CSS

**Frameworks**: Quarkus, Hibernate, Spring Boot, Jakarta EE, Java EE, Angular, Django, Flask, Ruby on Rails

**Technologies**: AWS, Lambda, ECS, Fargate, EC2, VPC, Cloudfront, S3, SNS, SQS, Kafka, Pipelines, Bitbucket, Git, Vim, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, Jira, Trello

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Principal Engineer, Red Pontis — 2022–Present

- Led a team of 6-8 engineers in designing and developing a tokenization service provided by Visa (VTS) and Mastercard (MDES), resulting in the elimination of penalty costs due to non-compliance with tokenization guidelines in the previous version and supporting over 2 million daily requests.
- Designed and implemented the new architecture with the premise of generating easily scalable and deployable applications, using AWS technologies such as VPC, ECS, ALB, ECR.
- Mentored junior, mid, and senior engineers, fostering their professional growth and ensuring the overall technical excellence of the team.

## Tech Lead / Senior Software Engineer, Quiputech — 2019-2022

- Designed, implemented, and maintained CI/CD pipelines for multiple projects on AWS in all environments (development, QA, pre-production, production), using services such as Bitbucket Pipelines and AWS Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2).
- Developed REST APIs for transportation companies and toll booths to accept debit and credit cards. The system supports over 150,000 daily users.
- Developed internal libraries for critical client aspects, such as an authentication system with AWS Cognito and RedHat SSO.

# Software Engineer, Saftec — 2018-2019

 Developed an accounting management system for a bank, where accounting entries are generated/refunded and sent to the SOAP service provided by the bank. The user interface was developed with jQuery, and REST APIs were published.

# **EDUCATION**

CIBERTEC — Computación e Informática, 2016 - 2018

Languages: Spanish (native), English (advanced), Portuguese (basic)

## **AWARDS**

- 2nd place in the DISRUPTIA hackathon 2017: The project's objective was to create a chatbot for a store on Facebook. Google Dialogflow was used.
- Best Java Project 2017: Project for the "Programming Language II" course. Application for placing orders with suppliers. I was a group leader and was responsible for coding in Java and using Bootstrap for the user interface.
- Best Angular Project 2018: "Integrator Project" course. Application for tutoring. We used .Net (Web Api) as a service, Angular as Front-End, and SQL Server as a database.